Chan Makara Chhaing

Phone: 0421 719 345 Email: makara chhaing@hotmail.com

Portfolio: https://makaracc.com
GitHub: https://github.com/makaracc

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/makara-chhaing

CAREER PROFILE

I am Bachelor of Information Technology graduate, I believe there are new skills I need to learn, and I would love to learn those skills to improve myself and help the team. I can adapt in team work very well from my past experiences especially in Agile environment.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Information Technology

July 2020 - July 2022

Deakin University, Burwood, Victoria

- Major: Application Development and Cyber Security
- Achieved: Distinction and High Distinction for all Programming units

Diploma of Information Technology

October 2019 - June 2020

Deakin College, Burwood

• Achieved: High Distinction in all subjects

EXPERIENCE

Research Assistant May 2022 – July 2022

Deakin, Burwood, VIC

- Collecting data to from survey done by 100 people on facial recognition device
- Communicating and following instruction from one supervisor and a mentor

Chief of Product Officer

March 2022 - June 2022

Deakin Gopher Industries, Deakin

- leading creation of opensource projects with agile
- Leading company alongside with three other leaders and arranging company structure size of 55 people
- Aligning company's products with company's missions and visions
- Communicating and applying ideas and goals asking by board of directors
- Mentoring teams with deliverables and explaining concerns related to software engineering
- Being a co-scrum master for company website project
- Looking after design, development, testing and deployment of website
- Learnt leadership skill and clearer understanding of agile culture from other leaders and experience

VOLUNTARY EXPERIENCE

Coding Mentor

February 2021 - May 2021

- South Melbourne Park primary school, Albert Park, Victoria
- Communicating with one STEM teacher to provide best possible learning experience to students
- Arranging and providing supports to more than 15 mentees for Scratch Programming
- Mentoring in a 2-hour session using story telling skill to draw attending to lesson
- Leading a group of about 10 students to work on a different project each week

INTERNSHIP

Front-End Developer Intern

December 2021 - February 2022

SummerTech Live, Australia

- Recruited by Deakin Launchpad to work on SummerTech for Medi-Ai company for one web development project
- Ensuring development of 20 frontend pages match with provided design
- Integrated Typescript and React to build frontend application and chatbot
- Adapting with agile culture in software development from planning to executing for three months' time

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

- August 2021 Al Acceleration Bootcamp, Deakin Launchpad, Australia
- July 2019 October 2019 Android Development, ITC institute, Cambodia
- March 2019 October 2019 Software Development, Step Academy, Cambodia
- August 2018 Diploma of Python at Step Academy, Cambodia

TECHNICAL SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Java |
 C# | C++ | Python | JavaScript |
 Typescript
- Git | GitHub

- Web Development: React | NodeJs | Express Js
- Android Development with Java programming language
- Algorithm: developed A start
 Path finding algorithm to create a
 path finding application
- Agile | Scrum master
- Cloud: AWS
- Security: OWASP basic and Wireshark

EXTRA CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

Al Tech Camp August 2021 - August 2021

Deakin-Launchpad, Burwood, VIC

- Won first place as a team of in competition for best pitch and usage of technology
- Labeled 50 images for classification in machine learning
- · Trained models using TensorFlow API for image recognition

International Virtual Hackathon

August 2020 - August 2020

Deakin University, Burwood, VIC

- Collaborated on one project with Deakin students and other students at different universities in China
- Designed one set low fidelity UI for web application and one set of high-fidelity UI
- Initialized one idea about application to work on for whole event

REFEREES

Available upon request